[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I hit the good pitchers pretty good, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I was just leading them, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't try to hit them out of the par.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I can't think of any one pitcher that I would say, there in the back, hope he doesn't pitch today or something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you must have batted against Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_02]: I liked him.
[SPEAKER_02]: You liked him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could hit him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when I was in the American League.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could hit Walter, I think, because I'm just leaping the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a good fastball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't have any spitter or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just threw that fastball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He always threw it over the plate, too, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I remember that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That one thing there, I don't know who else they had.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a nice fellow, Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember he titted with me once.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, God damn, I'm having a tough time getting you loud.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he wouldn't have.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you battle against Grover Cleveland Alexander?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was eight.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was...
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in the National League, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but he was...
[SPEAKER_01]: In this crime, I think I was in the American League, and he was in the National League.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, he was with Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Phillies.
[SPEAKER_01]: We played an exhibition series, I think, a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was Larry Lajoie like?
[SPEAKER_01]: Lajoie?
[SPEAKER_01]: Swell guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: easy going.
[SPEAKER_01]: He used to kid me a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: A great big fella.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was likeable.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, he's gone.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was Joe Birmingham your manager in Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_02]: How kind of a manager was Joe Birmingham?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have much confidence in him.
[SPEAKER_02]: They fired him, I know.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got fired, and I think a lot of people didn't have confidence in him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he came later.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was just trying to think who the manager was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the manager before him?
[SPEAKER_02]: Lagerweide, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: It had been Jimmy McGuire or Tommy Armour.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was trying to think who was the manager when I went
[SPEAKER_02]: It was Birmingham.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was thinking it was in 1913.
[SPEAKER_00]: It might have been.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Jedi was the Chapman, Ray Chapman played there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, well, did you know Roger Peckinpah?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Came up about the same time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Chapman came along about that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was the most exciting game or play or incident?
[SPEAKER_01]: Does anything stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_02]: I would think that double no-hitter, but that didn't seem to excite you very much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything else that stands out?
[SPEAKER_02]: An unusual play?
[SPEAKER_01]: I know there's something, though, that stood out.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I looked in those damn books, I could get it, but I just didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: My memory's so good that...
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything funny?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any real... Any funny plays or incidents?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any what?
[SPEAKER_01]: Funny?
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything that's funny that happened that you can think of?
[SPEAKER_02]: Crazy plays?
[SPEAKER_02]: Usually a lot of good stories about funny things happening.
[SPEAKER_01]: There weren't so many funny things in baseball in those years, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were serious and, you know, just trying to... How about Babe Ruth?
[SPEAKER_02]: You batted against him, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew Babe pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about Babe.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me about him a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't worry about a damn thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was just... Where was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: We played exhibition games together.
[SPEAKER_01]: In Hartford, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was dressing with the manager in the room.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did I tell you that story?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who the devil was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: And the bellboy came in, oh, we're both playing on the arts team, an exhibition game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what Dr. Stevens thinks.
[SPEAKER_01]: The bellboy, oh, he called.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll think of it in a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: He ordered some water.
[SPEAKER_01]: The bellboy comes in and put the water on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, and he put a dime on the table where they put the water.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a big plate, you know, in the bottom of the jar.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the kid wouldn't pick it up when he walked out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he got on the phone again and called, set up another Balboa, set up a Balboa.
[SPEAKER_01]: And what was his name?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, you want to, oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: He put a quarter out, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the kid wouldn't pick it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he walked out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, set up, oh, no, he didn't walk out.
[SPEAKER_01]: They stayed in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, send another bellboy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He sent another bellboy, and he put, I think, about 50 cents or something on the thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know whether I'm getting this story just right, but anyway, he finally didn't take it either, and he run him the hell out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, get out of here, you're custom, and he says, you're no damn good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were we talking about?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ruth.
[SPEAKER_02]: The babe.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, it wasn't babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who the devil was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, babe was too easy going.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd never blow anybody up.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a happy-go-lucky type.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why did you leave Cincinnati to go to Boston?
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Why did I leave Cincinnati to go to Boston?
[SPEAKER_01]: You traded or sold?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd like to look at some of your pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: You want to see who is in it with you?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's my two brothers, Willard and Walter.
[SPEAKER_02]: Are they still in the area here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But no, they don't live here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Willard lives up here in Watch Hill.
[SPEAKER_01]: Walter lives over in Glen Acres.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was very interesting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why don't you ask me about something like that, ma'am?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's been a while since we've heard that story.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a good picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: You hit a triple there, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: That wasn't very nice.
[SPEAKER_00]: Try to get in that one.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's the infield.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have any glossy pictures of that infield?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you have any pictures of this?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, glossy prints?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mean other pictures of that?
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I let my nephew down in Kentucky, Louis wrote, take the book,
[SPEAKER_01]: And then my niece brought it back.
[SPEAKER_01]: She lives out here in Loveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she brought it in today.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said I loved it, because I knew you felt you wanted to see it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I went through some of this old stuff in here.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's all kinds of write-ups in there about what I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of this stuff, I don't even...
[SPEAKER_01]: There is a book, too, I just... My sister had one, Helen Bressler, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: She married Rube Bressler.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And... She asked me, she said, do you want to take this?
[SPEAKER_01]: So I brought it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I found out, my wife said, you got one of those books.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a fixer, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I went in business with him, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we had put in Willa Rae Turner, that's Willard, Larry, and Rae.
[SPEAKER_01]: Down on Beachmont Avenue.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you come up?
[SPEAKER_02]: Beachmont.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you come up Beachmont?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you passed Honeysuckle Drive and Honeysuckle Lane, we put that in.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, of course, Beachmont is changed down there where Rube had a tavern.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, down at the end, where you turn now to go across the levee, a little further down, right across from our oil station.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I got out.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I brought my folks here from New Britain, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bought them a house down at the foot of Mount Washington Hill.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's an oil station there on it now.
[SPEAKER_01]: And my dad run the oil station for me, and I got in the United Petroleum Company and made me secretary.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was some mix-up downtown, and my attorney, Dolly Gruber, hell of a nice fella, got us out of the jam.
[SPEAKER_01]: Someone's trying to step in and take this.
[SPEAKER_01]: These fellas were from Lakeland, Illinois that started the United Petroleum here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got them out of the jam, and they took me in and made me secretary, see, in the United Petroleum Company.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, they're not active now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sold out later.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that's how I happened to get in the oil business, and I got started this station down the foot of Mount Washington Hill, see, and bought my folks a house down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: brought them here, brought my mother and dad and my two sisters.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Helen was the youngest, the one that married Ruth, and I sent her to school here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Frances, I got her a job with Charlie Brolin, an attorney.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how we got located here in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's when I was...
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know I had this.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wrote this down.
[SPEAKER_01]: Two years.
[SPEAKER_01]: I managed it a second year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Simmons Ball Club, Kenosha, Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_01]: My pitchers, Flip, Raleigh Maple, Dick Kerr.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've heard of Dick Kerr?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dobbins, Ketch, Beagle first, Crothers second.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played short with my brother Walter third.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ty Tyson, you've heard of him?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's an announcer.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played center field.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had two good years up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took my mother up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We lived in a lake just out of Kenosha.
[SPEAKER_00]: Played about two or three games a week.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't have any duplicates of any of this stuff, do you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't have any duplicates of any of these programs or pictures?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, a lot of them are in there, right upstairs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Duplicates?
[SPEAKER_02]: You have duplicates of anything?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, there's the oil station.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, paint.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's my dad on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think that's me and that's Ruth.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't see my dad on here, but there's a picture of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's the athletics, you see that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, there's a big picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's 1910, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's my roomie, Wally Shane.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a slow guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to visit with him up in Wales Centre, up near Buffalo, New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's your brother, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Herbert.
[SPEAKER_00]: Herbert.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got him when he was really little.
[SPEAKER_00]: What is that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Wall clearers of yesteryear.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's something I haven't seen about the basketball team, that team that I played on in the 50s.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of this stuff I haven't looked at for years, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: I've kept me busy for a month.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Could you spare any of these pictures?
[SPEAKER_00]: Could you spare any of these pictures for me to make copies of?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's you, right?
[SPEAKER_01]: These are both yourself?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about this one?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's Rube Bressler, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's Rube?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, that isn't Rube.
[SPEAKER_02]: Doesn't have a name, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Looks somewhat like him, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, it is.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's Rube.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where's this?
[SPEAKER_00]: The left fielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who the hell is the left fielder?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't know where this was?
[SPEAKER_02]: What ballpark that would be?
[SPEAKER_00]: That might be Middletown.
[SPEAKER_00]: My man is up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where was this town?
[SPEAKER_01]: Middletown?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I'm close to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was up there three or four years.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just played Sunday balls.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's Middletown.
[SPEAKER_00]: Geez, I never saw this.
[SPEAKER_00]: It says, there are many friends and admirers of William Hopper following his work as a member of the New Haven State League team.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is showing in a game that's hardly very good.
[SPEAKER_00]: This should show us that in itself.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, this is at Newark.
[SPEAKER_00]: What?
[SPEAKER_02]: Newark.
[SPEAKER_00]: Newark, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, where are you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know any of those fellows.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, you don't?
[SPEAKER_02]: You're in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Am I here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Aren't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: I hope so.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And how about Rio?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I think that's him here.
[SPEAKER_01]: The top of the back row.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see him now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yourself.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's me.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Rio.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
Huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very fascinating.
[SPEAKER_02]: Any ballplayer here?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gee, I don't remember reading this stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm just going to move this stuff over here.
Hold this down.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a funny guy, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Up signs are the athletics.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then it says here, puff for Bill Coff.
[SPEAKER_00]: You fill Eddie Collin's shoes at second.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Coff has decided to fill Eddie Collin's shoes at second base for a match.
[SPEAKER_00]: The team is pleased to have the making of a first-class goal player.
[SPEAKER_00]: This fella's up here pressed hands up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's co-paid for the hamster.
[SPEAKER_00]: Make no mistake about Coff.
[SPEAKER_00]: He played for the Mets under the name of Brady.
[SPEAKER_00]: And through the burden of all the games where he was tried, he was the bully-eye for the ball, and always has a hit in his stick.
[SPEAKER_00]: In addition, he is a finished infielder, and one that is required but unpolished to make into a gem of the purest ray, serene.
[SPEAKER_00]: Huff has a splendid head, and thus has all the brains and brawns needed to make a fine second baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never read some of this thing here.
[SPEAKER_00]: These write-ups.
[SPEAKER_00]: When would this have been?
[SPEAKER_00]: Middletown.
[SPEAKER_00]: What year would that be?
[SPEAKER_00]: Any idea?
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did I quit here?
[SPEAKER_02]: 19... 21, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is about 24.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: 25.
[SPEAKER_02]: I want to get a date on that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's when I was starting business here.
[SPEAKER_00]: All rides for the football back would have been made at 4.30 next Tuesday.
[SPEAKER_00]: 30 Husky boys will leave by auto for Hartford.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dinner will be served at Hartford's Harry Mellon's Café with hand-pulled ice when all four boxes on the right-hand side of the theater have been reserved.
[SPEAKER_00]: The automobiles will be fully directly installed.
[SPEAKER_00]: With the beginning of the basketball season.
[SPEAKER_00]: With the beginning of the basketball season, it's important to really think about security service and a good coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: To get the team in their championship form, several names have been suggested.
[SPEAKER_00]: Among those is William Clough.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mr. Clough is an old high school athlete.
[SPEAKER_00]: And since leaving school, he's made a new real record with baseball and basketball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never did much of a basic.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where were you for this one?
[SPEAKER_00]: What's that letter on there?
[SPEAKER_02]: It's like an I. Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_02]: When were you there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't tell you the year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't have your Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't have you down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was there, let's see, after I left Kenosha.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, that would be about...
[SPEAKER_02]: In reference to baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Baseball has changed things.
[SPEAKER_01]: Today, the new...
[SPEAKER_01]: Baseball has changed, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Today, the newspaper's changing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, for records, everything is records, records.
[SPEAKER_01]: We never knew any records.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nobody knew what we received in our salary or any of the details.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was private business with the owner, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And now, you might think I'm popping off wrong, but I want to give you this.
[SPEAKER_01]: because I think it's important, just my idea of baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I grew up in Connecticut, New Britain, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I lived before that in Winston, all through Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: My dad was a baker.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we lived in Winston, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was in the next to the last grade there.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they used to rehearse in a double room where the 8th grade and the 7th grade were together.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I knew they had to go down at the end of the season and take an exam to go to high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had to take an exam to get into high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I knew the date and everything, and I went down with the gang in the 8th grade.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm in the 7th grade.
[SPEAKER_01]: and took the exam.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I passed it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how I passed it, but I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have something that I passed.
[SPEAKER_01]: So a short time later, we moved to New Britain, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the school season was just starting in the fall.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so I entered high school as a freshman, which I shouldn't have done.
[SPEAKER_01]: because I skipped the last grade in grammar school.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I go to high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I only went to high school three years.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I started playing ball, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I went out for the baseball team, and I couldn't make the team.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I went out for the basketball team, and I couldn't make the team.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went up to the YMCA, and I set up pins.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the membership fee, I think, was $2 or $3 for students.
[SPEAKER_01]: So instead of after high school, I'd go up there and fool around.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the YMCA team, all seniors that had gone to college and all and were in business or something, working in New Britain, Connecticut, they took me along on their first trip to Stanford, Connecticut, near New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: as an extra man, a sixth man if someone got hurt, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I go along, and I'm still going to high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: And anyway, during the first part of the game, the one physical director there was the one forward and the manager and captain, a fellow named Slater.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they were getting beat pretty badly.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he got disgusted with the other forward because he couldn't pass him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Excuse me.
[SPEAKER_01]: My damn memory's slipping.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're the sixth man, Lon.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, Slater, the coach and right forward, got disgusted with Sandberg, the other forward.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he puts me in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was clever when handling the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we finally won the last and the second half.
[SPEAKER_01]: We beat them out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And from then on, I'm a regular on the YMCA team, champions of New England states.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the five states, Massachusetts, Connecticut, you know the states.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, anyway, so they begged me down to high school, after I played a couple of games, to go out for the team.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, why should I play with a punk team when I'm playing with a good team?
[SPEAKER_01]: So we play a charity game with the high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were winning down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so my gang says, on the YMCA team, we'll feed you tonight, kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we beat the devil out of them, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I scored, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not saying this.
[SPEAKER_01]: But there were as many points as the whole high school team put together.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they wanted me to plan the high school game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, why should I plan?
[SPEAKER_01]: That was basketball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Later I played professional basketball in Cohoes, New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was one professional league team in the United States at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I played there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was a kind of a substitute, but I got into several, I got into quite a few games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well anyway, then that fall,
[SPEAKER_01]: A friend of mine in high school that had one year at Fordham, Bill Walsh, his dad had a restaurant.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the one fellow in the restaurant, customer, an older fellow, his name was Patsy Burns.
[SPEAKER_01]: And his brother was connected with baseball in Chicago, Illinois, Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: in the, I don't know what the National American League offhand.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so Patsy said, told Bill, he said, I'll give him a job, a tryout with Lee Fole at Akron, Ohio, in the Class C League, professional team C. So anyway, I went to Akron.
[SPEAKER_02]: This 1910,
[SPEAKER_01]: About 1910.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were at Fordham one year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Wait a minute now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I went back to Fordham every winter after that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't finish my Fordham story.
[SPEAKER_01]: I ought to finish that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, anyway you want to tell it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I want to get it all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because how far did I get on Fordham?
[SPEAKER_01]: You interrupted me, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, you were just...
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't know, you were just going there, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, anyway, at Fordham, when I was playing baseball there, of course, this is before, when I was talking about this kid in high school and all, that was the head of Fordham, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: So, anyway,
[SPEAKER_01]: Walsh got me, or through Patsy Byrne got me this job at Agra.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I came back.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, and I'll tell you that, and I'll tell you a photo.
[SPEAKER_01]: It goes in rotation.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then Lee Fole was the manager, and I was a regular shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played, oh, I guess a couple of months.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I only weighed about 105 or 108 pounds, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was skinny, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess I got petered out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And one night I went down in Akron.
[SPEAKER_01]: The bats on the club were all pretty heavy for me, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's some kind of a store down there that opened on a Saturday night.
[SPEAKER_01]: It had a lot of athletic goods.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they had cheap bats and stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I bought a light bat, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I sneaked it in the clubhouse at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the next day I'm playing shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Foal says to me, he was the catcher and the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lee Foal.
[SPEAKER_01]: He later managed in the Bay Leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, what kind of a batch you got there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Billy.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was Billy then, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, let me see it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I handed it to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, you can't hit with that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a drugstore bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's no wood in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, the other batch are too heavy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he says, and he kind of just didn't say much more, but he called me aside the next day, and he says, you need a rest, and I can't afford to give you a rest.
[SPEAKER_01]: We can't carry any extra men.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'll have to give you your release.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, what are you going to do?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I says, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm not going home.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I live in Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, well, why don't you send Reel a telegram?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was with us as a first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who's this?
[SPEAKER_01]: Reel, R-I-E-H-L.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never played in the big league, but then he got this.
[SPEAKER_01]: They let him go there because Foale had this fellow Miller that was with the club the year before.
[SPEAKER_01]: He knew him real well.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he let Reel go.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Reel was managing Newark, Ohio in the Ohio State League, a lower league.
[SPEAKER_01]: Akron was in the O&P League in Class C. I was getting $125 a month.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, how do you send a telegram?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, don't you know how to send a telegram?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, I never sent one.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he wrote one up and sent it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we got an answer from Rio that reports from Newark, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were on the road playing Newark.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so on the train, going from Akron to Newark, I made up my mind I was going to bat left-handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could run, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so I get there just in time for the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Briel says, you're hitting second and playing short.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he was with the club while I was with Akron, and he knew just.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went up to bat left-handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, am I getting, and the man on first, nobody out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I have to get a ball in, said I'm going to pull it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got one in there, and I hit a line drive to right field and got a triple.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I finally scored and came in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rio says, I don't remember you batting left-handed at Akron.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, oh, sure, don't you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: I tell a lie once in a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was a swell guy, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, I'm the regular shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I switch hits, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could run.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I learned how to bump.
[SPEAKER_01]: He showed me how to bump.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got quite a few base hits bunting.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, I play about a month regular.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the team is bought by Indianapolis as a farm club.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they let Rio go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Am I talking just loud enough?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: Am I?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm talking a little loud.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know why.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, a new manager comes down.
[SPEAKER_01]: from Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he has some extra players that they bring down that they have lined up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know how.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, anyway, just about a week before this happened, our catcher busted a finger.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the Regal didn't have an extra catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I said, I'll catch for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: I used to catch when I was a kid, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went and called.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the fella's finger got better, and he kept me in catching.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I busted my finger.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when the Internet took over, I had my finger taped up, this one here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'd warm it up pitchers and so on like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I wasn't playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: The new manager says to me, did I say this is a repeat?
[SPEAKER_01]: said to me, what do you play on the club?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was getting close to September, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, well, he says, I want to talk to you on one of these days.
[SPEAKER_01]: And finally, the next day, he says to me, I want to talk to you
[SPEAKER_01]: The office, they had a little office in Newark down in the center of the town, upstairs.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, you're getting too much money.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've got to take a cut.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I can't take a cut.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I live in Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm going to get all the dumb answers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything he asked me, I'd give him a dumb answer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Finally, he got disgusted with me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he wrote out my release.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, here, here's your release.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm sitting on this side of the table.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's on the other.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, you mean I'm fired?
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, you're fired.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, you have nothing more to do with me, have you?
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, you're a dumb manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm no catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm a shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, all I want is my release.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember his name?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember his name.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never did know his name.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anyway, Indianapolis sent him down.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, I go back home, and it's the 28th or 29th of August.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the season, the amateur season, I mean, the teams quit on the 1st of September, a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I go to Springfield.
[SPEAKER_01]: My home is in New Britain, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: Springfield, Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were in the Connecticut League, Class B.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I go out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I later knew the manager real well.
[SPEAKER_01]: I asked the manager, I said, how about giving me a chance to try out with you?
[SPEAKER_01]: My finger was feeling pretty good then.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, I'm awful busy now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't bother me.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I sat on the bench and watched the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: The next day I go out.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had one more day before the September 1st.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I had to do something.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went out and asked him again.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, are you busy today?
[SPEAKER_01]: Can you talk business with me or something?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said no.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he didn't have any good, you know what I mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: So I go back to New Britain.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I meet my friend Bill Walsh, who had one year at Florida.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill says to me, and he pitched on the Fordham team, he said, you never get the big leagues unless you go to college.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, how the hell can I go to college?
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't even graduated from high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, we'll fix that up.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they had a summer home down at Ocean Beach near New London, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, come on, we'll go down to the beach for a couple of weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we went down to the beach.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we come back.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a fellow named Brady, Frederick Martin Brady, in his class.
[SPEAKER_01]: They went in business with his dad in New Britain.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, that year, that summer, I played ball with New Haven, and they sent me to Fall River on option.
[SPEAKER_01]: Class B. I got $150 a month with me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And at Fall River,
[SPEAKER_01]: I played third base and I had a good year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I can't think of the manager's name now.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, I got it in the barren book there somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, at the end of that year, I go to Fordham with Brady's diploma.
[SPEAKER_01]: Frederick Martin Brady.
[SPEAKER_01]: So every Brady they called King, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: So I became King Brady.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I played on the baseball team, and I played on the basketball team.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we're playing this game this day, the last game of the year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I get a message from the Sands, from a scout for Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said he wanted to stay on the bench after the game, and he wanted to talk to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the rest of the team left.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I waited, and he came down, and he says, what the hell, what was his name?
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't think of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, we bought your release from New Haven.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was the property of New Haven.
[SPEAKER_01]: They loaned me the Fall River, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, Cleveland's in town today, in a couple of days.
[SPEAKER_01]: You get out of school tomorrow, and they'll be here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I want you to come down to the hotel and join the Cleveland team.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, in the meanwhile, in that couple of days, he talked to somebody, I don't know, a reporter or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they had a big article in the paper, King Bernie of Fordham bought by Cleveland, or something to that effect.
[SPEAKER_01]: And his right name is Billy Coffsey.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he played with professional ball and had put it in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the priest calls me in, the dean at the college.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he lectured me for, I guess, 15 minutes.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I can't understand you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You act so nice and everything, and you take somebody else's diploma and come to college.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you can't do anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I didn't say a word.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'm going to see you tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_01]: After he called me online, he said, I'm going to see you tomorrow morning.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went in the next morning, and I finally says, Father, and I give him a little bit of my history.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, if you were me, what would you have done?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I would have done the same thing you did.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he says, I want to find out if you want to come back here and get an education.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't care about a diploma.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you don't care about playing on the teams.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can help coach the baseball and basketball teams.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I enjoy that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that's what I did for about three years.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, let's see, where did I go then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Toledo, next stop, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Toledo.
[SPEAKER_01]: Athletics, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, Toledo.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then they
[SPEAKER_01]: Cleveland Farming Toledo.
[SPEAKER_01]: Toledo was a farm club, an association.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I played on the Toledo team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then Connie Mack bought me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I'm with the Athletics and I'm playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: First I was a utility man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm on a $100,000 infield.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bowery, Baker, McInnes.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were with them when they won the pennant that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: They won the pennant, right.
[SPEAKER_02]: They blew it to their brains.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, oh, at that time, a new league started.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they were approaching the players.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Harry Davis was the former captain on the athletes, but he was the coach.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he liked me, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he called me on the side.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, now we're going to have a meeting with some of the fellows.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was the name of that league?
[SPEAKER_01]: Federal.
[SPEAKER_01]: Federal League in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: The athletes was Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, I'll get the dope for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'd be fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But a little later.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did I say I was getting in Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't say.
[SPEAKER_01]: $150 a month, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, oh, yeah, then they raised me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went and saw Connie.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, everybody's getting a raise.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, don't you think I ought to get a raise?
[SPEAKER_01]: So they gave me a raise, $175 a month, a $20,000 award.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, the next paycheck, he says, it'll start right away.
[SPEAKER_01]: So my next paycheck was the same as it was before.
[SPEAKER_01]: The raise wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went, Connie used to sit on the bench in the civilian clothes, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never put a uniform on.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never saw him in a uniform.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he was mad at me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he says, what do you mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, oh, and he kind of bawled me out, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, Mr. Mack, you promised my raise would start as soon as I signed the contract.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, if you're not satisfied, he said, you let me know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm satisfied, but I thought I should let you know that there was a mistake in my paycheck.
[SPEAKER_01]: So a week later, he sent me or so to Baltimore with Jack Dunn.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, I'm down there in Paul and Lauren Plain, and then I go to, oh, and I'm sold in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me something else.
[SPEAKER_02]: What about the Federal League offer?
[SPEAKER_02]: They never made me an offer.
[SPEAKER_02]: You met in Chicago with some people there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who did Harry Davis take you to in Chicago?
[SPEAKER_02]: Who'd you meet with there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Hoosiers was giving me the dope.
[SPEAKER_01]: His coach on the team.
[SPEAKER_02]: Davis?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Harry Davis.
[SPEAKER_02]: And did you have a meeting, though, with anybody else from the Federal League?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Joe Tinker, anybody like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Never did.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think that I remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: And anyway, then I go to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were sold by Connie to Cincinnati?
[SPEAKER_02]: Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, by Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was with Baltimore, but I guess Connie had... What was it like in Baltimore?
[SPEAKER_02]: What was Jack Dunn like?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played short.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had a pretty good year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1960.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was switch hittin', you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could run.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought I'd drag Bundy a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could do that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And anyway...
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm just trying to think of Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, anyway, I go to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Christy Matheson is the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I join the club.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we're in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_01]: And in the clubhouse, there's a private room that he has.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then down here is all the lockers and the different players.
[SPEAKER_01]: Christy says, I want to see you.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went in the private room.
[SPEAKER_01]: He sent the boy out, and he said, I want to play it, and you've got to sign a contract.
[SPEAKER_01]: I hadn't signed a contract since then.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he got a contract.
[SPEAKER_01]: and I signed it William L. Cobb.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had one name, William, that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: My dad's name was Lorenz, L-O-R-E-N-Z.
[SPEAKER_01]: Matty says, what's the L stand for?
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, Larry, Lorenz.
[SPEAKER_01]: I might have said Lorenz, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, he says, hell, your name's Larry.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, all the great hitters were Larry.
[SPEAKER_01]: Larry Doyle, Larry Gladwell, Larry somebody.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he fixed me after I signed the contract.
[SPEAKER_01]: out in the lobby, gives me the locker, and introduces me to everybody as Larry.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I became Larry.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was going to ask you about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: What kind of a manager is Christy Mathieson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Wonderful.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most wonderful fellow I met in baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was encouraging, he was gentle, and
[SPEAKER_01]: You couldn't help but like him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was he a tough enough leader, though?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, you gotta be tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: But everybody liked him.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Connie Mack as a manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: Connie was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't say much.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he had his things in an easy, gentle way.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody called him Mr. Mack?
[SPEAKER_01]: I forget that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, uh...
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, tell me about the double no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: In Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jim Vaughn's pitching.
[SPEAKER_01]: Fred Tony's for us.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm playing sharp.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we go to nine innings, nobody gets a hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wasn't everybody excited about this?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't know, we just went along, didn't pay any attention.
[SPEAKER_01]: So in the tenth inning I come up and I get a line drive to right field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of these raggots say it was a grounder between the first basement and the second basement.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought, the way I remember it, I don't know, I might be wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, I hit the first.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did Vaughn do when he got that hit?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he react, you know, did he blow up or yell at you or anything?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I didn't pay any attention to that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, I find the, oh, somebody hits the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: fly balled in one of the outfielders, and it was an error, see, and I went to third.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, uh, Jim Vaugh- uh, Jim, uh- Thorpe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thorpe was up.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he hit a swinging punt just to the- to the right of the pitcher's box.
[SPEAKER_01]: They write it up different.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, uh, he goes over, and I had a good jump.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a walking start, and I went in the run, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he tries to get me at the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: There wasn't an article in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a wild throw, or the catcher wasn't expecting the ball, or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And anyway, I scored.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then Tony shut him out in the last inning, so we won 1-0.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's the only double-hit game, no-hit game, that's ever been played in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_02]: What'd Tony say when he got back?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he say anything?
[SPEAKER_02]: Tony, when you scored that run, was he excited?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he didn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nobody's excited.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tremendous game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, they all pat me on the back.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nice work, kid, that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, it was just natural.
[SPEAKER_02]: A double no-hitter, though, and not much excitement, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: But everybody was friendly, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, getting away from the subject, what do you write on baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm writing this biography of Ben Johnson, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_02]: I write little stories about unusual things that happen.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've written a story about unassisted triple plays, and I've written some stories about no-hit games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to show you this.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know, but it might be a benefit to you, you know, that you can.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Batting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now today, you can correct me if you want.
[SPEAKER_01]: Today, they're using a light bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long, man?
[SPEAKER_01]: And they're like this.
[SPEAKER_01]: See?
[SPEAKER_01]: High over the shoulder.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they're stepping in this one spot on every pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Straight ahead.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wide stance.
[SPEAKER_02]: Step into it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they swing it, lining up like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's my impression.
[SPEAKER_01]: I might be wrong.
[SPEAKER_01]: But as much as I've watched them, I think I'm right.
[SPEAKER_01]: See how they're long.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now what did we do?
[SPEAKER_01]: For instance, I use a kind of, not a long bat, but a radish model, I think it was, anyway, and it's a heavy bat, and I choke up a little about that much.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I hold the bat right here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And now today they wear masks and everything else to protect themselves.
[SPEAKER_01]: We never worry about getting hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because we're watching the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: If the ball's right at me, I just go like this.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever get hit in the head?
[SPEAKER_02]: Nah.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, close.
[SPEAKER_01]: They couldn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: They throw it behind you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, behind me.
[SPEAKER_01]: If they're behind me, I just go like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Quick reaction.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I'm watching.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm watching that pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just like you're throwing to me as hard as you can.
[SPEAKER_01]: You throw here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to the ball, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm shifting.
[SPEAKER_01]: Today, the reason for it is they're here, and they step in that same spot, and they're swinging like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there comes the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're not in a position to dodge.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're off balance.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, what do we do?
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, the ball is on the outside corner of the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: Say it's a strike.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm watching that ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: There it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm stepping over that way and I'm hitting from there.
[SPEAKER_01]: From my tail.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm using my body.
[SPEAKER_01]: There.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now the ball is on the inside.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not stepping in the same place like they do today.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, it's on the inside of the strike.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm switching this way with my eyes following the ball, I'm stepping there, and I go like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're not getting their body into the ball today.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what you're saying.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're not using their body, they're using their arm swingers.
[SPEAKER_01]: And most of them are on the end of the bat, and swinging from their tail.
[SPEAKER_01]: Trying to hit home runs because they're writing you up.
[SPEAKER_01]: and giving them a lot of recognition.
[SPEAKER_02]: What kind of hits did you get mostly?
[SPEAKER_02]: Line drives?
[SPEAKER_01]: Line drives.
[SPEAKER_02]: To all fields?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You could place the ball to right field?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't try to place it except on a hit and run.
[SPEAKER_02]: When you're batting left-handed, could you place it down the left field line?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Batting left-handed, I did the same thing, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: That ball's on the outside, I set it there, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's on the inside, there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you strike out much?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very subtle.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good eyes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why I didn't hit you much either.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't see anything else.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about bunting?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bunting?
[SPEAKER_01]: Lost guard.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a bad way to put it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think I got a... Now...
[SPEAKER_01]: Here was my favorite.
[SPEAKER_01]: You sit in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I may never get up.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll just watch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Stand.
[SPEAKER_01]: Left-handed seat.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I was in a slump or wasn't hitting good, here's what I'd do.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm up to bat.
[SPEAKER_01]: And just before he pitches, I step up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, the umpires back here, they never call me
[SPEAKER_01]: They might today call you out for stepping out of the box.
[SPEAKER_01]: The box perhaps was there, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I go like this, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: You get a good jump.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I try to get the ball down to make the pitcher cover or field the ball, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or the first baseman field that the pitcher has to cover.
[SPEAKER_01]: I could beat him every time.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the slump, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, bunting, the secret of bunting is, I'll bunt right handed.
[SPEAKER_01]: The top hand, you just lay the bat in the hand.
[SPEAKER_01]: You just lay it there like that, and this one is loose.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then you're there, there's the ball, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And over here, it's on the inside, you're bunting down the third baseline,
[SPEAKER_02]: You just leave it there, and this is loose.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, left hand the same way, same principle.
[SPEAKER_01]: Both are loose, and this is just a guide.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now for instance... Today they're afraid of getting hit on the hand.
[SPEAKER_01]: They can't hit me on the hand, there's space there, over a foot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I'm watching that ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: See what I mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: And today, take and throw them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And field them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I want to show you this.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, the ball is here, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, here's what they do today.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's why they get sore arms.
[SPEAKER_01]: They reach out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, what did we do?
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball's there, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: See my feet?
[SPEAKER_02]: He moved over.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, the ball's right at me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Today, what did they do?
[SPEAKER_00]: What did we do?
[SPEAKER_02]: See my feet?
[SPEAKER_02]: They put their body in their throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the ball was here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Today, it's there.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did we do?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's footwork.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who taught you most about fielding?
[SPEAKER_02]: Any one player?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you just learn it by watching?
[SPEAKER_01]: Jack Browery was a great shortstop.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did he teach you something?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, they didn't teach, they didn't tell us much.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'd ask questions, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I never got a sore arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Eddie Collins?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you learn from him?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a great ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: I watched him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was perfect on double plays, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: First of all,
[SPEAKER_01]: He's over here at second, and he comes over to... Now he's going to take a throw from the shortstop, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball's here, you touch the bag like that and throw it, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball's here, touch it like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: The footwork's there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They all had that then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Baker didn't have so much on third, but Collins and Bowery, they did.
[SPEAKER_02]: You played behind Barry, did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: You played behind Barry.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was Utility Man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played 40 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think about 40 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, today the gloves they got.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have you seen the gloves?
[SPEAKER_02]: I see them in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're incontinued.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's no fingers.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just a big bag, practically.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it, I think it imparts to the player to reach and play that way.
[SPEAKER_02]: Instead of moving over for the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Instead of, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Instead of.
[SPEAKER_02]: Big glove will take it in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Instead of using your fingers.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's probably no good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think it affects fielding records at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think it affects their fielding records?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do they pick up more than they would otherwise?
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't get the footwork.
[SPEAKER_01]: They can't go over to the right if they're playing short and throw out a guy at first base like we could.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because after we went over to the right, we got that in and we got our body in there, the whole work, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Today they're throwing like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why they get sore arms.
[SPEAKER_01]: See?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think, that's my opinion, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where did you coach?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: What schools did you coach, again, baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: I coached Xavier here.
[SPEAKER_02]: You coached at Fordham, you said.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I coached at Georgetown University in Washington.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was that, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: I went from here.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, after I got, I went in business here and I played with Armco here, Merkin Rolling Mill, that Middletown semi-pro team.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is after you threw in the big leagues?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played short and managed.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think I went to Penn and I think around here for semi-pro.
[SPEAKER_02]: You went into business?
[SPEAKER_01]: But you know, I left Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: I gave them 10 days notice.
[SPEAKER_01]: And went to Kenosha, Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I managed up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why'd you do that for?
[SPEAKER_02]: Why'd you leave Boston?
[SPEAKER_02]: Any particular reason?
[SPEAKER_01]: We were a tail-end club.
[SPEAKER_01]: We weren't doing anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got a good offer up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: At the Simmons Bed Company, Kenosha, Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_01]: You knew somebody up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: They saw me play, I don't know where, anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know just how I happened to go up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't manage the first year.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was my second year, see, that I managed.
[SPEAKER_02]: That'd be about 1924, maybe?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's OK.
[SPEAKER_02]: Your last year at Boston was 1923.
[SPEAKER_02]: Your last year at Boston was 1923, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a book.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where the devil is it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's OK.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got it here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, here it is.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, the encyclopedia, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Hayes, Roush, Hayes.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were in Dayton, 2nd Basin, Georgetown.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I gave notice up at Dayton, I think, that I was going to leave.
[SPEAKER_01]: What were you doing up at Dayton?
[SPEAKER_01]: Playing an exhibition game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I had this offer from up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know through who or I got in my write-ups.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the manager of Boston that last year or so?
[SPEAKER_02]: Remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Let me see.
[SPEAKER_02]: What'd they say after they got your notice?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fred Brady.
[SPEAKER_01]: I blame the Clevelands.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then they sent me to Toledo, that's right, and Philadelphia and Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_02]: What'd you ask me?
[SPEAKER_02]: About your 10-day notice, what did they say about that in Boston?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm trying to think who the devil that manager was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't like it, I know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you can't do that or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, you can give me ten days' notice.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, you can give me ten days' notice.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's in your contract that way, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: If it's in your contract, you can give ten days' notice.
[SPEAKER_01]: So anyway, then in Kenosha, I had all big league players.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a list in here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, are you a pretty good cook?
[SPEAKER_01]: See, my wife and her two nieces left.
[SPEAKER_01]: She said, now you can eat some soup.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't have to go out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got it on the pad there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Are you in a hurry to go?
[SPEAKER_02]: I scheduled a talk with Jess Haines this afternoon.
[SPEAKER_02]: With who?
[SPEAKER_02]: Jess Haines.
[SPEAKER_01]: St. Louis he played all the time, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Since 1918.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was here in 1818.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were in military service.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were in the army.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you probably didn't see him.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've seen one.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've just been reading about...
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got a story to tell you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I want stories.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, I managed in 18...
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't play.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got this job at Four River Mass.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Kennedy's my boss, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Kennedy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Kennedy.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Joe Kennedy?
[SPEAKER_01]: The Joe Kennedy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a baseball above him.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I joined up there through some scout in Massachusetts, near Springfield or...
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't think of the... Oh, Haraway, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, uh...
[SPEAKER_01]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I wrote down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, see, I was thinking about wondering what dope you wanted.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wants everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was trying to think of some of the players I had up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went up there, and I managed the team, see, and played shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I had Ken Nash.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a judge.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've heard of him, haven't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: From near Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he played third.
[SPEAKER_01]: Clyde Engel, first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: Al Mammel and Dutch Leonard were my pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ken Nash, third base.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jacobson, came from New Britain, he was a... Baby Dahl?
[SPEAKER_02]: Baby Dahl, Jacobson?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I think it was a different one.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was another one, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Merwin Jacobson.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Merwin.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think the scout that recommended me was Jack H-A-R-A-H, Harrah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just wrote that down.
[SPEAKER_02]: You played with Fall River then during the war.
[SPEAKER_01]: So then, wait a minute now.
[SPEAKER_01]: At Fall River.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did they have a shipyard there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Shipyard?
[SPEAKER_01]: Fuller River.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was an article of paper yesterday.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here, I got it here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Quincy Mass.
[SPEAKER_01]: Methane steel plant.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a team there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Joe Kennedy was the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he used to say to me, they put me in a room up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: phone and everything, even the girl's secretary.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so we practiced, and he'd come out, he loved baseball, and he says, can I sit on the bench?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, if you keep your big mouth shut, you can.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the way we were, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the most wonderful fellow I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sunday, I'd play at Hartford, Connecticut, semi-pro ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd get $150 a game.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: The pitcher's got $100.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd pick a pitcher down, either Dutch Leonard or Al Mamadou, the one that didn't work the weekend.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd take the other one.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I made them split.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had an old Stutz car.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd drive down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I lived in New Britain, 10 miles from Hartford.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, they'd go back to Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'd go to New Britain and stay overnight, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this game that we were playing there, the fellow on the draft board lived not too far from where we lived.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's a friend of mine.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he didn't like to come down after the game Sunday.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he came up the house, and he says, you know, Billy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, it was Billy then.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, you're in the next bunch that's going to be drafted.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I says, all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I said, gee whiz.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, thanks for telling me.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I get back, and I tell Joe Kennedy, I said, Joe, I said, I'm in the next bunch that's going to be drafted down in New Britain.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I live in New Britain, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, what do you want to get drafted for?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, what am I going to do?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'll get some dope for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: In about a week, he had the dope.
[SPEAKER_01]: from Kentucky, the field artillery schools, the training school for officers.
[SPEAKER_01]: And instead of me being drafted, my bunch, they left in about a month, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I played.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, then I left.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know just when.
[SPEAKER_01]: But our season was about over up there, and I went out to Camp Taylor in this field artillery school.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did me a big favor, perhaps the biggest favor anyone ever did me in my life.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's in Kentucky, Camp Taylor?
[SPEAKER_01]: Camp Taylor.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were there for how long?
[SPEAKER_02]: How long were you at Camp Taylor?
[SPEAKER_01]: Just a little, then the war was over late in the season, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were up at Quincy all during the 1918 season.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then towards the end of it, you were at Camp Taylor.
[SPEAKER_02]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then in the spring, then I got a breezy meal with a roommate.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just died here a short time ago, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He, oh, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Brooklyn tried to sign me then.
[SPEAKER_01]: They said, when I was still up at the Far River, they need to shortstop, see, and they wanted to sign me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, no, he came out to the camp, that's what they said.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then how was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, then they sent me a contract.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a rotten contract, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I told him I wasn't interested.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then they sent me another.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I got a letter from Greasy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, don't sign with Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was something in the paper, I guess, that Brooklyn was going to sign me or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, we can get you back on the Reds and get you the dough you want.
[SPEAKER_01]: So then I
[SPEAKER_01]: In 19, I signed with the Reds and I came here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you move here about then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: When did you move here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Here?
[SPEAKER_02]: To Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jesus, now you got me.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me about the World Series now.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1919 World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: Where to begin?
[SPEAKER_02]: Hard to find a place to begin, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Now what do you want to know about it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, what was your feeling during that series about the... Oh, not a thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not after the series was over, not that off the winter or the spring.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't think that none of the players or anything, we'd be doing... sick of that at all.
[SPEAKER_02]: Weren't there rumors in the papers, though, that the White Sox weren't playing very hard or anything?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Judge Landis was in there then, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he came a couple years later.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he?
[SPEAKER_01]: To me, he was always horseradish.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm riding on the train once.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're riding him up now, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Going from Jacksonville to... We're training in Florida.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it happened, he was going through the car, going to the...
[SPEAKER_01]: diner, and he steps and he says, uh, you're Billy Cough, aren't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, yeah, the judge.
[SPEAKER_01]: I says, uh, he said, I'm going up in the lead.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why don't you come up and eat with me?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I'm figuring I'm going up in the diner.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went up and ate.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the only nice thing he ever said to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, uh, so I forget what I talked to him about.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm thinking, oh,
[SPEAKER_01]: They were training, I think, at St. Petersburg.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were having a banquet there, or dinner or something out in the field, in the open.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Landis is making a speech.
[SPEAKER_01]: I forget just what year that was.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's looking right at me, and Dick Rudolph is sitting in front of me, and he said, I had the pleasure of
[SPEAKER_01]: I was sitting with one of the fellas here in the club, and he bawled me out about something.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's the only time in my life that I didn't jump up and challenge.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wish I had.
[SPEAKER_01]: Billy Southworth was on the club then, the captain.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think Fred Mitchell was the manager.
[SPEAKER_02]: This would be Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: This Boston.
[SPEAKER_02]: That'd be 22 or 23, probably.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me more about, there must have been something during that World Series, some good stories you could tell about those games?
[SPEAKER_02]: Batting against Eddie Seacott?
[SPEAKER_01]: Claude Williams?
[SPEAKER_01]: Nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought of that often, you know, to think about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I talked to some of the players, Mike Breesing and the ones I knew real well.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did they think or say?
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't surmise a damn thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't figure it out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they couldn't have beaten us that year, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had something that you don't see on a ball club very often.
[SPEAKER_01]: We had fellows like Lawrence Rath that never got much credit, the second baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little fella.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's the greatest second baseman I ever played with.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played with Langerway, and I played with, uh, uh, oh, who the hell, with Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, darn, he never made a mistake.
[SPEAKER_01]: He always, he answered that ball perfect, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rath.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just a little fella.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little uptime hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was important to the club.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's our leadoff man.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I think he got more base on balls than any man in the league.
[SPEAKER_01]: He scored more runs because he's on base all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was your lineup?
[SPEAKER_02]: Positions.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who played first base?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll give you the lineup.
[SPEAKER_02]: Look at that scrapbook.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's my brother Herb.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you have another brother?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Walter played with the New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got him on there later with McGraw.
[SPEAKER_01]: McGraw was strong for me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you like McGraw?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a battler.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jake Daubert first.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Daubert.
[SPEAKER_01]: Honey Grove.
[SPEAKER_01]: There I am.
[SPEAKER_01]: Morris Rath.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's Renfield.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Eddie Riley, Squeegee Neal.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Rube.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pat Duncan.
[SPEAKER_02]: Duncan Yeltsin.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't see Duncan on here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are catchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a line-up.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, look at that picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's the athletics team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Middletown girls beat New Britain.
[SPEAKER_01]: What the hell?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that's up in Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hi, Negro, that's me.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's Morris Rapp and Jake Dauber.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's Steve Dauber.
[SPEAKER_01]: I did a line-up.
[SPEAKER_01]: There I am.
[SPEAKER_01]: My brother Herb, he's at WNJ.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got these write-ups.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, this book here, my niece brought it back today.
[SPEAKER_01]: She had it out.
[SPEAKER_01]: S. Greasy, W.M.J.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here we are.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's Walter and Willard and myself.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, here's a line-up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rath, Daubert, Grove, Roush, Duncan, Koff, Neal, Reardon, Eller.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, Wingo was a catcher, too, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, what'd I do that day?
[SPEAKER_01]: I got one hit, one stolen base, four put outs.
[SPEAKER_02]: So Jake Daubert was your first baseman?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What kind of ball player was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't have a lot of power hitters, though, did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Wasn't too much power in that team, was there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Or was there?
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of good line drive singles hitters.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: We all kind of, I think, used our footwork in those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: The way I kind of showed you, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it came...
[SPEAKER_01]: There wasn't anybody on the club that was on the end of the bat and swinging from their tail that I remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the best hitter, would you say?
[SPEAKER_02]: Eddie Roush?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was the best hitter on that team.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had the best average always.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Chicago, Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that the World Series?
[SPEAKER_01]: Koff?
[SPEAKER_01]: Score a four to two.
[SPEAKER_01]: Billy Koff knocks out three base, hitting fourth, and scores two runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Plays a one-on-one game.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know where that's at.
[SPEAKER_01]: Top front is 10 yards.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that's where it's at.
[SPEAKER_01]: Rath, Daubert, Gros, Roush, Duncan, Conquest, Chicago.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you know Joe Jackson?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever know Joe Jackson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was Joe like?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He left-hand hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he could run.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he very smart?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know that, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't... You never talked to him much at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was he with?
[SPEAKER_01]: What team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: The World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah, and he worked in the league when I was with the athletics, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, that's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he would be in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was young then, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was with Cleveland then, the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he played in that World Series, and I was wondering if you... Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Buck Weaver.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Eddie Collins, too, then.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he played against Eddie Collins in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Collins with him then?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was one of the... who didn't get in the scandal.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in the scandal?
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was one of the...
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't figure him being in the scandal.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a right fielder named John Collins who was also not involved, but most of them were.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was hoping to get some good stories out of that World Series and all the things that happened then.
[SPEAKER_02]: What about the next year when the story broke?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you remember much of the reaction then when you first read in the paper that those games had been thrown?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did it come out the next year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it came out about a year later, just on the eve of the 1920 Oral Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when it was first became publicized, although there were rumors all year long about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wonder what you fellas thought about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we didn't pay much attention to it, I don't think, you know, as far as that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, even after we heard about it, it didn't seem to hit us that
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, there's certain fellas that we couldn't believe it, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the toughest pitcher you had to hit against?
[SPEAKER_01]: The toughest pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Spitball pitchers.
[SPEAKER_02]: Any particular one?
[SPEAKER_01]: A spitball pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know what a spitball pitcher is?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but any one pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there any one name that was tough, particularly tough?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember now.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you know what a spinner did?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it dipped.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it come up and boom.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Burley Grimes?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you bat against him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, they spit on the... Where is it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Right on here, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And they keep their hands away from the seams.
[SPEAKER_01]: And this comes off, and the power, it isn't too fast a ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, they can't get the real speed on it like a regular fast ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: But these fingers slide off, and the ball comes up without rotating.
[SPEAKER_01]: And just as it gets to the plate, it drops.
[SPEAKER_01]: About that much, some of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's funny, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you think we ought to bring it back in?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think it's tough on the arm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because it isn't a natural throw.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Gripes had a long career.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Carl Mayes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Carl Mayes, right.
[SPEAKER_02]: So there was no pitcher that stood out as the toughest one that
[SPEAKER_02]: I need a single picture.